no I'm using the mic so that the sound
quality is a little better I have
ordered a lapel pin so I should be
coming in the next week or so so today I
want to talk about the difference
between capitalism and communism and how
you find purpose in that
so in capitalism you choose it you have
to pay for your own education and you
need to make the trade you need to make
your own decisions and the trade-offs
between you don't want to pick something
I make money at or do I want to pick
something that calls to me and for some
lucky people those are the same thing
but for many people they have to make
that trade-off and so some people
thrives under capitalism they're able to
find that they're able to find purpose
and profit and other people are added
aren't happy but are making lots of
money and other people are happy but
they aren't making happy but not making
lots of money or at the opposite this is
the trade-off
there's also competition in under
capitalism so you succeeding is somebody
else failing where there's only one job
that we're all competing for or a set
number of jobs that are all competing
for and for the group for the business
that needs to bring in the right people
you have to pay that price you need to
if you want quality employees you have
to pay a higher price under communism
the government decides who what you do
so based on the society's needs and your
talents they assign you a job and that's
the job you get and it doesn't matter if
you're happy at it I mean everyone's
making the same amount of money at it so
the happiness money trade-off doesn't
exist but you're also not tapping into
um but it doesn't exist because you get
neither really so that's not a great a
great trade-off a system that is
possible is to honor both the individual
and the group my balls in cheap ones
like a hare City know that our summer
so for the individual we can create
tools and systems that help them
discover their talents if they don't
know or do you know what they are
helps them find groups and projects that
are meaningful to them and that they are
compatible with it helps them we can
help people learn learn what they want
to learn in a way that works for them
and each individual within a system like
that is able to do 90% plus what they
love doing what calls to them and not a
job description that's possibly 50/50 or
worse than a 90/10 split and it's 90
plus I'm saying here in groups in that
new system we can create tools to help
the group work more effectively so it
can help we can help we create tools to
help people find compatible
personalities or any compatible talents
like you all the same personality and
all the same skill set you're probably
not going to be super great doing a
project together because you're not
going to have like everyone's going to
want to do this financed or everyone's
gonna want a geographic design instead
of having that diversity we can create
tools when I say we're to work more
effectively together that helped with
the project management or help with
conflict resolution that we can create
those tools together those are not high
in the sky ideas all of those things can
be coated in all of those things they're
different things they're not the first
ones we're gonna be creating but we can
help each other because in a society
where we've tapped in to true human
individual potential given the
individual all the same what they get to
do and yet they still get to contribute
in a way that's meaningful to society
because we're able to help them figure
out where their skills are usable so
it's not about having a job description
to fit in it's about fitting in who you
are as an individual what your talents
and limitations are and find other
people that are compatible with that who
make up for where you lack their
personalities are compatible so everyone
can find a space that works for them and
every
group can come together and have
individuals that make up an amazing
group which means together globally
working with that system individuals are
more happy and we all get to benefit
from that we all get the innovation and
efficient efficiency like the energy
that comes from working your purpose
from not having to have that trade-off
between money and happiness where we're
meeting all of our needs with other
tools that we talked about other videos
and at the same time we have a human
need to contribute so if you're given
the tools to be able to contribute at
your level and your interests people
want to contribute and especially if
you're able to do it in a way that's
meaningful to you whether that's by
yourself or whether that's in a group
and help finding the group and
maintaining the group so that is a bit
of what how someone would find their
Colleen or how we can help each other in
the world and yeah again just tapping in
to the full potential of the individual
helping them be happy helping them find
what makes their soul sing and allowing
them to do that we're not in competition
with each other
everyone's succeeding in helps us
succeed because now we have their
amazing ideas to work with and their
amazing ideas because no one can be you
and so any project made up of those
specific individuals is going to be
unique in a world where we've tapped
into that and we've created the groups
that harness that we can solve every
single human problem every single
economic environmental rather easily and
rather quickly because what I can't do
other people can and we work better when
we have that hive mind so it's a little
bit of my thoughts today see you
tomorrow